In comparison to our planet.
和我们的星球相比
In comparison to our universe.
和我们的宇宙相比
As individuals, we appear small and insignificant.
作为个体，我们显得渺小而无足轻重
Like a grain of sand in a vast desert.
如茫茫沙漠中的一粒沙
But we are more, we have the power to make a difference.
但我们不止于此，我们有能力做出改变
United as one, we can change everything.
团结一致，我们可以改变一切
Everyone can do something.
每个人都可以有所作为
It's not a time when we can just sit and watch the world go by.
如今已经不是我们只能坐等世界流逝的时代了
We're all connected. Each of us, we have our role to play.
我们都是相连相通的，每个人都有自己的职责
We are one planet, and it's our differences that make us stronger.
我们同居一个星球，正是我们的差异使我们更加强大
When we combine our individual efforts towards the same goal.
当我们把各自的努力结合起来朝着同一个目标前进时，
The result is greater than the sum of its parts.
其结果将会大于部分之和
It always seems impossible until it's done.
在没有做到之前，这些事情看起来总是不可能的
And to do it, we all have to take that step forward together.
为了成功，我们所有人都必须一起向前迈出那一步
And the more of us that try, the closer we come to succeeding.
努力的人越多，我们就越接近成功
Together, we will win the race against climate change one step at a time.
齐心协力，我们将一步一步赢下对抗气候变化这场比赛
Extreme E's very own floating paddock, the Saint Helena.
Extreme E（极限电动车拉力锦标赛）独特的漂浮围场——St. Helena号
is on route to Saudi Arabia
正在前往沙特阿拉伯的途中
carrying the cars and event logistics for the first stop of its global Odyssey.
为环球跋涉的第一站运送车辆和后勤设施
After leaving Liverpool in the United Kingdom and passing through the Mediterranean.
离开英国的利物浦后，经过地中海
It had reached the engineering feet, that is the man made Suez Canal,
它已到达了那伟大工程苏伊士运河的脚下
connecting Europe to the Red Sea.
其连接着欧洲和红海
The key to the Suez Canal is that ships actually can access the Middle East, the Far East
选择苏伊士运河的主要原因是，船可以直达中东、远东
without having to go round the bottom of Africa and around South Africa.
而不用绕过非洲的底部和南非
There's no need to do that, so there's a big time saving,
没有必要这样做，所以节省了大量的时间
and also, of course, a big fuel saving.
当然也节省了大量的燃料
Because it's a lot less miles.
因为距离更短
Everyone's come together as a team,
每个人都要齐心协力作为一个团队
and that's the only way with a smaller crew
这是在船员较少的情况下
that you'll get all the jobs that are needed to be done on the in the canal.
而完成所有需要在运河上进行的工作的唯一方式
Everything has really been at first for St. Helena,
对Helena号运输船来说，所有的事情都将是第一次
there's always an element of pressure, there's always an element of a challenge.
总会有压力，总会有挑战
I've been on board down for two and a half month,
我已经在这里待了两个半月
I don't think there hasn't been a day where I haven't had a challenge,
每一天都有新的挑战
but there also hasn't been a day that I haven't enjoyed.
但我也享受这里每一天
On reaching the Saudi Arabian ports of Jeddah after weeks at sea,
在海上航行数周后，抵达沙特阿拉伯吉达港口
it was time to unload the nine electric race cars and fifty containers from the ship.
是时候从船上卸下9辆电动赛车和50个集装箱了
I'm just absolutely shocked.
我惊住了
And amazed and ecstatic and happy all at once,
惊讶、狂喜和快乐同时涌上心头
you know the journey that we've been going to to bring in the St. Helena back to the UK.
我们把Helena号带回英国
to refitting it to getting it ready
改装一下，做好准备
and now to see our cars beautifully delivered into Jeddah for our first race.
现在看到我们的这些车，被完美的运送到吉达进行第一场比赛
What an amazing achievement from everybody,
这是大家共同努力的结果
both shoreside and everybody at my team on board to see these wonderful cars,
无论是在岸上的工作人员还是在我船上的团队，看到这些漂亮的赛车
and a great step forward for season one with Extreme E.
这是Extreme E第一季迈出的伟大一步
Fantastic achievement.
这绝对是非凡的成就
At a junction between Europe, Africa and Asia.
在欧洲、非洲和亚洲的交界处
Saudi Arabia is a vast country occupying the majority of the Arabian Peninsula.
沙特阿拉伯是一个幅员辽阔的国家，占据了阿拉伯半岛的大部分地区
The ancient city of Alula sits in the northwest corner of the second largest desert in the world.
古老的阿卢拉城坐落在世界上第二大沙漠的西北角
First founded over two and a half thousand years ago.
它建立于2500多年前
It became an important stop on the incense road,
是“香料之路”上的重要一站
welcoming weary travellers to its natural oasis.
迎接疲惫的旅客来到它的自然绿洲
But underground water sources such as these are becoming rarer
但是，在年年都变得越干越热的环境中
in an environment that is getting hotter and dryer every year.
这样的地下水源变得越来越稀少
Deserts are enormous.
沙漠是很广阔的
About 40% of the world is dryland region,
世界上大约40%的地区是旱地
and around thirty something percent of the world's population lives in these regions.
而世界上大约30%左右的人口生活在这些地区
It's not an easy life, so making that life harder is the difficulty that we face.
这种生活并不容易，这是我们所面临的困难
Desertification is the process of degrading the land as it dries out.
沙漠化是土地干涸后退化的过程
In the future, we'll see with the desert's expanding,
未来，我们还会看到沙漠的扩张
Observed land and sea surface temperature record shows us
陆地和海洋表面的温度记录显示
全 球 地 表 温 度
温度差异
（1961-1990平均值）
12个月连续平均值
95%置信区间
that warming is around a degree C over the period from 1860.
从1860年开始，气温上升了大约1摄氏度
And we've proven, twenty twenty five years ago that that's due to the increase in carbon dioxide,
经过证明，25年来这是由于二氧化碳量的增加
but in the future, towards the end of the 21st century,
但在之后，接近21世纪末
we see marked warming in the subtropics of the world.
我们发现亚热带地区明显变暖
根据1951-1980
预测2080-2100
温度变化情况
大 气 温 度
up to sixty degrees C across the deserts of the Arabian Peninsula, north Africa, and also in southern Africa.
在阿拉伯半岛的沙漠、北非、非洲南部，有些升温高达6摄氏度
This region of the world warms far more than the tropics.
这些地区比热带地区变暖情况严重得多
Our fortunes are going to be bound up in what we've done to this climate system.
我们的命运将与我们对气候系统的所作所为息息相关
it's both the question of mitigation and adaptation.
这既需要缓解，也需要适应
We need to slow it down,
我们需要减缓气候变暖的进程
and we need to be able to deal with what we've committed ourselves to.
同时我们也要有能力承担自己所造成后果
Situated a few miles outside the city.
位于城外几英里处
The site for the first ever Extreme E X-Prix was coming together
第一场极限电动车拉力大奖赛即将举行
with great care taking place to respect the stunning backdrop of the desert surroundings.
同时也会小心地保护沙漠的壮丽景观
For founder and CEO, Alejandro Agag, this moment represents the end of four years of planning.
对于创始人兼首席执行官Alejandro来说，这一刻代表着四年计划时间的结束
And his feelings of finally being able to go racing was clear.
他对成功举办赛事的态度很明确
Feels great relief,
感觉如释重负
I mean, we're finally here. It's been a lot of work,
我们做了很多工作，终于来到这里
a lot of curve balls to us. COVID, Brexit, the Suez canal, you name it,
经历了很多波澜：新冠疫情、英国脱欧、苏伊士运河堵船
所有你能想到的这些困难
We made it. We're here. First Extreme E race.
我们都克服了。我们现在来到这里，举办首场Extreme E赛事
Many times, I felt that this could stop or could fail,
有很多次，我都觉得这可能会半途而废
but luckily, we had so much support. That's why we made it.
但幸运的是我们得到了许多支持，这就是我们成功的原因
We've been able to bring the incredible names of motorsport to a completely new concept,
我们将许多赛车界名宿带到这个全新的概念中
and all with the same mission.
出于一个初衷
Make it become a platform to, you know,
让它成为一个平台
bring as many people as possible on the journey towards climate action through sport.
让尽可能多的人通过运动赛事走上环保之路
Then I think it will be beautiful tomorrow.
未来将会是很光明的
With site built well underway,
随着场地建设的顺利进行
the next job was to test the course that had been designed
下一项工作是测试赛车场
with the help of two time DTM champion, and Rally Cross driver Timo Scheider.
其设计工作是在两届DTM冠军，拉力越野车手Timo Scheider的帮助下完成的
This would be the first time the all electric Odyssey 21 car would be tested on a competitive course.
这将是第一次纯电动的Odyssey 21赛车在一条充满挑战的赛道上进行测试
We are trying to figure out the track layout with this real car.
我们要用这辆车摸清楚这条赛道的布局
And on the other side as well, for the technicians and for the car,
另一方面对于技师们和赛车来说
I think there are some fine tuning things We need to look at.
我认为还需要进行一些微调
It feels a bit like a world premier somehow, being the first guy hitting out with the Odyssey 21.
这感觉有点像首秀，作为第一个真正上手开Odyssey 21的人
Now they are on the first track ever.
现在这些要踏上它们的第一条赛道
It's a very nice feeling, so I'm really looking forward now to jump into.
这种感觉很棒，所以我现在很期待上车一试
The 8.8 kilometer circuit winds its way between these huge piles of sandstone.
这条长达8.8公里的线路在这些砂岩之间蜿蜒而行
Constantly undulating up and then down some seriously steep sections.
不断上下起伏
With the mix of gravel, dirt and soft sand for its tires to deal with,
轮胎要应对碎石、泥土、散沙这些不同路面
the first ever Desert X-Prix will provide a huge challenge for the cars and their drivers
这对于车辆和车手都将是巨大的挑战
After a few laps, the test and reserved drivers, Timo alongside compatriot Jutta Kleinschmidt,
几圈后，测试车手Timo与副车手Jutta Kleinschmidt
were happy with how much of a challenge the course would be.
对于这条赛道的挑战性，他们感到很高兴
To be honest, it's very tricky, and you have to find your way,
说实话，你必须认清自己的路
especially when you don't know the track well, this can be a huge challenge,
尤其是当你不完全了解赛道的时候，这是很难做到的
and you have chance and you have um-
你将面临各种机会，你将面临-
-Many options, right?
-各种各样的选择，对吧
So the gates are quite wide, so you can go right and left,
检查点的门很宽，你可以选择向左或者向右
you have many options, so that's super nice, I guess.
选择很多，我觉得这样很好
So this gives a lot of option for the drivers.
这会给车手更多的选择
The track is set up in a perfect condition right now.
赛道现在处于一个完美的状态
From the pure feeling in the motions, I have to say this will be super super nice.
从车辆的动态来看，我认为这条赛道会特别特别的棒
Extreme E is a venture into the unknown for everyone involved.
Extreme E对每一位参与者来说都是未知的冒险
But none more so than seven times Formula One world champion Lewis Hamilton,
对于七届F1世界冠军Lewis Hamilton更是如此
who has set up his own team for the first time.
这是他第一次组建自己的车队
It's very hard sometimes to believe in something, if you can't see it.
有些事情如果眼不见就很难相信
Wouldn't it be great to be a part of something that really does make a difference?
参与到这样一项有意义有影响力的事情中不是很好吗？
Where I am in my life, I'm looking to see how I can have a positive impact on the planet.
在我现在的生活阶段，我想努力对这个星球产生一些积极的影响
Over the last ten years, there's been a huge focus on education,
在过去的十年里，人们对教育越来越重视
people understanding what is happening in the world is becoming more and more of an issue.
人们对世界的认知越来越重要
I've grown up in normally aspirated engine world,
我是在自然吸气发动机的世界中长大的
like, I love V12s, I love V10s, I'm never going to love an electric car.
我爱V12，我爱V10，我永远不会喜欢电动汽车
Then I got an electric car, and they are so much fun,
然后我就有了这么一辆电动汽车，这些车开起来一点也不枯燥
it's so impressive, the power delivery is no delay.
马力的输出没有任何滞后
That's probably the biggest shock is just how much torque you're able to get.
最令你吃惊的可能是那巨大的扭矩
Now I'm converting all the cars that like Mercedes, providing, I want it to be fully electric.
现在我正把所有的车，比如梅奔赞助的一些，转向电动化
Sport has an opportunity to help raise awareness. There is a platform.
体育可以帮助提高社会认知，这是一个很好平台
And the reason I really love streaming, we're taking off two boxes.
我喜欢流媒体的原因是
You get to do the racing, the entertainment and fun stuff.
我们一方面可以去赛车，做这些娱乐性的事
But actually at the core of it, the real reason that we're there
但当中的本质，同时也是我们能这样做的真正原因
is to raise awareness for the issues that are in those places.
是为了提高人们对这些地区中问题的认识
I've grown up in motor racing my whole life since I was eight.
从8岁起我就是在赛车中长大的
It has been a male dominated sport.
赛车就一直是一项男性主导的运动
It still is a strongly male dominated sport,
它现在仍然是一项明显男性主导的运动
and I really think that that needs to change.
我真的认为这一点需要改变
There are a lot of young girls out there
要让更多的年轻女性知道
that need to know that there is opportunity for them in motor sport.
她们在赛车运动中是有机会的
I'm really excited to see a difference that they bring and the message that we're able to project.
我很乐于看到她们所传递出的不同的信息
My role is more like the, I would say the visionary,
我的角色更像是一个梦想家
I know what I want, I know how I want my team to look.
我知道我想要什么，我知道我所希望的团队是什么样子
I'm trying to put together the best team.
我在努力组建一支最优秀的团队
The first time I've ever had to choose drivers.
这是我第一次需要去选择车手
From a drivers perspective, I'm always looking for someone that's pushing the limit.
作为车手，我一直在寻找那些敢于推向极限的人
We got Cristina Gutiérrez, having won multiple championships,
我们有Cristina Gutiérrez，她已经获得多个冠军
and leading the first state of the Dakar rally.
在达喀尔拉力赛的第一阶段处于领先位置
Reliability and consistency is very, very key.
可靠性和稳定性将是非常非常关键的
Going to these places where understanding how to look after the car in those climb is going to be key.
在这些地方攀爬要求要懂得保护车辆
So I think that she's going to be a great asset for the team
所以我认为她会是团队合适的人选
Sébastien Loeb, nine time world champion. He dominated the rally world.
Sébastien Loeb是九届世界冠军，他几乎统治着拉力界
They know what to do in the car, I can't tell them what to do in the car,
他们知道在车里该做什么，我不可能指导他们
but in the back, setting off the team, making sure that we've got the right people
但在幕后，我要带领团队，确保我们有正确的人手
so that we deliver over and above.
这样我们才能有正常甚至超常的发挥
I could have only ever dreamed of owning a team.
如果没有这次机会，我可能只能梦想拥有一支车队
It's quite an exciting new prospect that that I think is,
我认为前景可期
you know, it can be exciting for people to see something different.
从不同角度看事物总激动人心的
The track was set.
赛道已经设置好
The drivers and their Odyssey 21 cars were ready.
车手们和他们的Odyssey21赛车准备好了
It was finally time to see what this unforgiving track was made of
随着各团队开始进行试跑
as the teams headed out for shakedown.
终于是时候看看这是一条怎样残酷的赛道了
I'm super excited for this track.
我很期待这条赛道
I mean, the first drive, you've probably seen a lot of the drivers stopping on this big,
毕竟第一次跑，你可能会看到很多车手停在
almost cliff, really, just down, like a huge, big side, almost a roller coaster.
这个巨大的下坡前，几乎是悬崖一样的地方，简直像过山车
Made it, you know, pretty spectacular to look at,
这也让赛道看起来非常壮观
and it's going to be super exciting to drive, I think.
这条赛道跑起来一定会特别刺激
The course is absolutely insane.
这条赛道很疯狂
I was actually quite shocked with what they put in, you know.
我惊讶于赛道中容纳的元素
Sometimes motorsport can go on the edge of safety,
我知道有时候赛车运动如同走在安全的边界上
but that drop is definitely pretty steep.
但那个下坡实在是够陡峭的
The biggest challenge will be being able to be spontaneous and adapting to the changing environments.
最大的挑战将是如何自如地驾驶并且适应不断变化的环境
That's really going to test our skills and that sense.
这绝对是对我们技能和赛车感觉的考验
The track is really extreme.
赛道真的很极端
The surface is really changing, so there are challenges all over the track,
赛道表面时刻都在变化，所以赛道上处处都是挑战
but that's what Extreme E is all about.
但这就是Extreme E的精髓
We need to put the drivers, the car and the tires to the limits.
我们要把车手、赛车和轮胎推到极限
The landscape is amazing, I already knew from Dakar.
这地方的风景很棒，我跑达喀尔的时候就有所了解
It feels good to be in a terrain more familiar to me.
在自己熟悉的地形比赛上感觉不错
If you never been in the in the sand before, it's a bit scary.
如果你之前从来没有来过沙漠，你可能会觉得有点害怕
For me it's normal. I-I think this is not a problem,
对我来说这是家常便饭，我已经习惯了
I'm excited to start, but also be, you know, nervous, because here it's everything new.
我很期待比赛开始，但同时也很紧张，因为一切都是全新的
Many things to to think about.
有很多事情需要考虑
I have everything to learn.
我有很多东西要学
Shakedown is the only chance of the teams to try and get to grips with the car and set up
试航日是车队唯一的机会摸清楚车的抓地力，并做好调整
before they would push it to its limits a day later in qualifying.
以便在排位赛中把车发挥到极限
Unfortunately for Segi TV Ganassi Chip racing driver, Kyle LeDuc, he pushed a little too hard,
但不幸的是，对于Ganassi Chip Racing车队的车手Kyle LeDuc
他推的有点过于激进了
And quickly learned that this desert track takes no prisoners.
并很快意识到这条沙漠赛道容错率极低
Guys, big crash, big crash,
兄弟们，有事故，有事故
I hit the big rock on the split line guys.
我撞到分割线上的石头了
It was a big mistake on my behalf, pushing too hard on a session that I didn't have to.
这是我自己的一个重大失误，我本来不需要在这一节推的这么狠
It was a very bad first day for us, something we're definitely not proud of.
这对我们来说是非常糟糕的第一天，绝对不是什么值得骄傲的事情
There is no way but up right now, so we're excited,
但是现在没有退路，只能继续向前，所以我们仍然保持兴奋
eyes up wide awake, throttle to the floor.
保持清醒，油门到底
We're in Saudi Arabia for the first ever Extreme E Desert X-Prix.
我们来到沙特阿拉伯第一次进行Extreme E的比赛
Before we get into the first competitive action,
在我们进入第一场比赛之前
the drivers were welcomed on board the St. Helena,
车手们被欢迎到Helena号上
where Extreme E scientific committee member Carlos Duarte
在这里，来自阿卜杜拉国王科技大学的
Extreme E科学委员会成员Carlos Duarte
from the King Abdullah University of science and Technology,
在这里，来自阿卜杜拉国王科技大学的
Extreme E科学委员会成员Carlos Duarte
had put together a program of environmental education
组织了一场关于美妙但脆弱的红海生态的教育项目
about the incredible yet threatened Red Sea ecosystems.
I'm really motivated by the mission of Extreme E.
我受到了Extreme E初衷的鼓舞
The main project that Extreme E has adopted in the Red Sea
Extreme E采纳的主要项目
is a project aiming at observe globally relevant population of sea turtles from climate change.
是观察气候变暖对海龟数量的影响
So there's two main species of turtles in the Red Sea,
红海中主要有两种海龟
one is the green turtle that feeds on sea grass
一种是以海草为食的绿甲海龟
and is the most abundant of the sea turtles in the Red Sea.
它们是红海中数量最多的海龟
And the second is critically endangered hawksbill turtle
第二种是濒危的玳瑁龟
that is one of the most endangered animals in the ocean.
这是海洋中最濒危的物种之一
So the turtles come out from the water to lay their eggs,
海龟从水里出来产卵
and they do that for the first time thirty years after they're born.
这是它们出生三十年来第一次的产卵行为
But they have high fidelity to the same beach,
但它们对同一片海滩有很强的归属感
so after thirty years of roaming the ocean, they will come back.
所以在海洋中漫游了三十年后，它们还会回到
within 150 meters from the place they were born.
离他们出生地不到150米的地方
And they will lay eggs there for the first time,
它们将第一次在那里产卵
and they will continue to do that every three, five years through the extended life span.
此后每三五年它们都会在这里产一次卵，直到生命结束
So when the eggs hatch, then they do an extreme race.
所以当卵孵化时，它们会进行一场极限的比赛
They have to do it, that's maybe a twenty second race.
这是它们必经的历程，可能只是一场大概20秒的比赛
But it's a race that they are able to win it.
但这是它们有能力赢下的比赛
The reward is a sixty to ninety year of happy life in the ocean.
奖励是60到90年的快乐海洋生活
We found in two consecutive years, there was more than 90% mortality.
我们发现在连续两年里，海龟幼崽死亡率超过90%
Because very rapid sea level rise with climate change.
因为随着气候变化，海平面会迅速上升，
Then the areas that used to be safe for them to lay their eggs are becoming prone to be flooded.
导致那些曾经对它们来说很安全的产卵地变得容易被海水淹没
At every race location,
在每一个比赛地点
Extreme E will be working together with local organizations to leave behind a positive legacy.
Extreme E将与当地组织合作，留下积极的影响
And in Saudi Arabia, it is collaborated with the Bar Foundation
在沙特阿拉伯，它将与Bar Foundation合作
to help preserve an important turtle nesting site
帮助保护受到海平面上升和塑料污染威胁的重要海龟产卵地
that is threatened by sea level rises and plastic pollution.
And some of the drivers were taken to have a look for themselves.
有些车手亲自去查看
Let's go save the turtles!
我们去拯救海龟！
We scientists have a very small voice.
我们科学家的声音很小
We don't reach audiences, we have very little influence,
我们不接触观众，我们的影响力很小
so Extreme E is translating that science into action.
所以Extreme E把科学转化成了行动
And it's only fitting that Extreme E main form operation is racing,
Extreme E作为一种大家喜闻乐见的赛车形式，十分适合与我们合作
because the window to solve the problem is narrow is rapidly closing.
解决问题的机会越来越少
So now we have a race,
现在我们有一个与气候变暖之间的比赛
a race for a future for the world, a future for our children and grandchildren.
一项为了世界未来，为了我们子孙的比赛
And we need to plan that race carefully,
我们需要小心地计划这场比赛
because we have not one second to lose, and we must win it.
因为我们没机会输，我们必须赢得这场比赛
From an ancient species that had been roaming the earth for hundreds of millions of years.
从一个在地球上游荡了数亿年的古老物种
To a cutting edge racing machine
到这台顶级的赛车终于准备好首次在沙漠中驰骋
that was finally ready to take on the desert for the first time in competitive action.
Before it does, let's take a closer look at some of the technology behind it.
在此之前，让我们具体了解一下它背后的一些技术
Extreme E's revolutionary electric SUV, the Odyssey 21
Extreme E的革命性SUV——Odyssey 21
极速
加速
重量
is designed to take on perhaps the toughest challenge in motorsport.
被设计用来接受赛车运动中最艰难的挑战
The all-electric machine will race across and through mud, sand, rock, water and snow.
这辆纯电动的机器将驰骋泥地、沙地、石地、水洼和雪地
From the heat and humidity of the desert and tropical rainforest
从炎热的沙漠和潮湿的热带雨林
to Arctic tundra and glacial base.
到北极苔原和冰川地带
The Odyssey 21 is an outstanding feat of racing technology.
Odyssey 21是当今科技的杰作
The car's battery, produced by Williams® Advanced Engineering,
车的电池来自于威廉姆斯
stores 40 kilowatt hours of usable energy.
可储存40千瓦时的可用能量
To put that into perspective,
换言之
the stored energy of this device could keep 2600 phones charged for a week.
这台设备所储存的能量可以让2600部手机充电一周
电池
储能
高性能
锂离子
40千瓦时
可用能量
The equivalent of a five hundred and fifty horse power combustion engine.
配备的电机相当于一台550匹马力的内燃机
It's capable of creating 1000 N·m of torque.
它能产生1000 N·m的扭矩
It's very powerful, quite reactive car, so you feel so fast about the dunes on the gravel.
这是一台非常强劲，非常灵活的车，在沙丘上跑起来感觉飞快
It's impressive.
很震撼
The Odyssey 21 is equipped with duel motors feeding the front and rear axles independently.
Odyssey 21配备有双电机，独立向前后传动轴输出动力
The driver can move the torque balance between the motors directly from the cockpit.
车手可以直接从驾驶舱调整扭矩平衡
This allows them to maximize energy efficiency to the wheels,
这有利于他们根据速度、抓地力和地形
单电机最大功率
扭矩平衡  可调
depending on factors like speed, grip and terrain.
来最大化能量效能
So that's a bit about what powers the car
这是关于车的一些知识
But what about the racing format of the five X-Prix championship series?
那么五场X-Prix的赛制是怎样的呢？
An Extreme E race consists of two laps.
一场Extreme E赛事包含两圈
The male and female driver must complete one lap each in any order,
男女车手必须以任意顺序各完成一圈
and can choose at the last moment who starts.
并且可以在最后一刻选择谁出发
Each team has two hyperdrive power boosts they can activate on lap one and lap two of the race.
每支队伍有两次PowerBoost的使用机会，他们可以在这两圈内进行使用
Day one is qualifying.
第一天是排位赛
Session one sees all nine teams do two laps.
第一节九支车队都要上赛道
One from each of their drivers.
每支车队中，每位车手一圈，共两圈
Session two sees all the teams head out to the course again.
第二节所有车队再次出来到赛道上
The time set from both sessions are then combined to make up the qualifying order,
两节的综合成绩将决定排位名次
and with it, the first championship points of the weekend.
同时，第一名将获得周末的首个积分
The top 3 go straight to the semifinal
前三名直接进入半决赛
Fourth, fifth and six go to the Crazy Race,
第四、五、六名进入Crazy Race
with the bottom three heading to the Shootout to decide the last three finishing places of the weekend.
最后三名进入Shootout，来决定周末比赛的最后三名的次序
Day two start with the semifinal
第二天是半决赛
With the top two finishes proceeding to the final,
前两名继续进入决赛
leaving one spot up for grabs to be claimed by the winner of the crazy race.
剩下的一个位置由Crazy Race的赢家代替
The team that crosses the line first in the final wins the X-Prix,
决赛中首个冲线的队伍将赢下本场X-Prix分站赛
taking with it the glory plus twenty five championship points.
同时获得宝贵的25分年度积分
All five X-Prixs count towards the overall team's title.
五场X-Prix分站赛后的总积分决定年度车队总冠军
But in the driver's championship,
但在车手排行榜中
competitors can drop their worst result of the season in their bid to be crowned the first Extreme E champion.
参赛者可以将本赛季最差的结果赌在可能的冠军车队上
Now you're up to speed on how the racing works.
现在你知道比赛是怎么进行的了
It's time to see what happened when the drivers took to the desert course
下面来看看在排位赛中，车手们在沙漠赛道上的表现
and drove their Odyssey 21s in anger for the first time,
这是他们第一次以冲刺模式驾驶Odyssey 21
as they headed out for qualifying.
First to set a lap was Lewis Hamilton's team X-44,
第一个做出成绩的是Lewis Hamilton的队伍X-44
who set a super fast time to set a high standard for the others to chase.
他们做出了一个极快的标杆成绩
Next to take to the dunes was Veloce Racing.
接下来出场的是Veloce Racing队
Stéphane Sarrazin took the start
Stéphane Sarrazin率先驾驶
with W Series champion Jamie Chadwick waiting in the command center to take over for the second leg of the run.
W Series世界冠军Jamie Chadwick在指挥中心等候接手第二程
Unfortunately for her and the Veloce team,
不幸的是
Stéphane hits a tree root as he sped away from the drop and had a massive crash
Stéphane在下坡段后撞到了一颗树根，导致了一次严重车祸
damaging the roll cage of their Odyssey 21 irreparably.
严重损伤了车辆的防滚架
And ending their weekend.
终结了他们的周末
There was more drama to follow in qualifying.
接下来的排位赛仍是精彩不断
Andretti United Timmy Hansen set a great opening lap.
Andretti United车队的Timmy Hansen跑出了一个漂亮的出场圈
but just before he handed over the car to Catie Munnings,
但是就在他把车交给Catie Munnings之前
he picks up a slow puncture on the rear tire.
他遇到了一个缓慢的保胎
The right rear's gone down on the car,
车的右后胎挂掉了
you can see it flailing about,
你可以看到车胎飘来飘去
I wonder why the dust was so much.
我还奇怪为什么甩出来这么多尘土
So Catie Munnings is now going to have to manage that puncture.
那么Catie Munnings需要处理好这个爆胎
Look at this.
看看这场面
Catie is still on a big push.
Catie Munnings仍然在推
Come on Catie.
加油Catie！
The tire is off the rim.
轮胎已经脱离轮毂了
It is off the rim.
确实已经脱离了
she's on the lock stocks both ways round.
她不断地左右打死方向
Now she's just got a few meters to go to make it to the finish line.
现在只剩下几米撑过终点线
Brings the car home, brilliant drive.
成功把车带回，漂亮！
We obviously had a slow puncher, just at the end of the first sector,
我们在第一段后面显然遭遇了缓慢爆胎
I went over a crest and the rear just snapped,
我过沙丘的时候后胎就直接撑不住了
and from then it was just you know on the rim the whole way back.
之后就全是靠着轮毂撑回来的
In that moment, every second count,
从那一刻起，分秒必争
so I tried to drive as far as I could,
所以我努力开快
but, you know, it's a long race, so we're not kind of given up yet.
但这是一场漫长的比赛，我们还没就此放弃
ACCIONA Sainz put together two strong issue-free laps
ACCIONA Sainz车队完成了无失误的两圈
to put them into a close second place behind X-44.
紧随X-44排在第二位
ABT CUPRA Mattias Ekström looked calm and fast
ABT CUPRA车队的Mattias Ekström看起来沉着而迅速
to put the team within touching distance of a top three qualifying time.
与前三名的速度十分接近
Claudia Hürtgen took over the car and was looking strong
Claudia Hürtgen接手后看起来颇具竞争力
as she headed towards the finish.
飞速冲向终点线
Seven seconds now, the gap to Sanz and Sainz,
与Sanz和Sainz的成绩仅差7秒
she is now approaching the end of the lap,
她正在接近本圈的终点
so this is going to be close all to play...
这将会十分接近...
Oh, side ways went into a roll.
哦！车身横过来直接翻了！
Massive off.
严重失误！
That's huge.
重大事故！
Claudia Hürtgen has had a huge crash.
Claudia Hürtgen遭遇了严重的车祸
Claudia just rolled really badly, I hope she's good.
Claudia刚才的翻滚很剧烈，我希望她没事
The ABT cars just had a big crash,
ABT的车刚刚遭遇了严重事故
so uh yeah, they've not said if she's okay or not, yet.
他们目前还没有报告她是否安全
Finally, we've seen Claudia Hürtgen out the car,
我们终于看到Claudia Hürtgen从车里出来
and you can see the guys there from ABT CUPRA big sigh of relief.
你可以看到ABT CUPRA的队员长出一口气
That is the best piece of news we've had all day.
这是今天看到最好的消息了
For sure, those pictures looked very wild and crazy
从画面上来看确实很恐怖
I'm super happy that Claudia is in one piece,
我很高兴Claudia能安全无恙
and it also shows that the car is pretty safe when you have an accident like that.
这同时也告诉我们，当你出现了这样的事故时这辆车是多么的安全
I'm here, I feel fine,
我没事
I hope the guys, uh can repair the car for tomorrow,
我希望他们明天比赛之前能把车修好
and then we will go out again tomorrow.
我们明天再战
The crash meant there was plenty of work to do for the ABT CUPRA team
这次事故给ABT队带来了不少的工作
as they tried to fix their car ready for action the very next day.
他们要修好车为明天的比赛做好准备
And even the tires was getting stuck in to get the car race ready.
赛前要把轮胎都装好准备比赛
With the track clear once again,
赛道再一次被清理完毕后
Rosberg Extreme Racing headed out to try and go top of the standings.
RXR队出场拿到最快成绩
Molly Taylor set out first and put it all on the line.
Molly Taylor率先驾驶，全程保持在赛车线上
Oh, rear end flys high.
车尾甩的很高
Go on Molly Taylor!
加油Molly Taylor！
Absolutely lit.
表现太亮眼了
Before she hand it over to Johan Kristoffersson
在她把车交给Johan Kristoffersson之前
to try and bring home the top spot in an incredibly tight battle with X-44.
以继续冲刺与X-44争夺第一名的位置
And is Kristoffersson, who takes first place .
Kristoffersson第一名带回
and Kristoffersson and Taylor, they absolutely nailed this first qualifying day.
Kristoffersson和Taylor他们赢下了第一天的Q1
What a drama it was, right until the end.
太精彩了，直到结束
Attention all teams, attention all teams.
所有队伍注意，所有队伍注意
From the stewards,
裁判的判决
the penalty for Rosberg is 60 seconds.
RXR队罚时60秒
44 kilometers per hour in the switch zone.
换人区内车速44Km/h
A penalty has taken the leaders from the top of the board, and its's going to drop them down.
罚时直接导致他们从榜首位置掉下来
Disappointment for RXR.
对于RXR是个很令人失望的结果
But despite that penalty, they still qualified within the top three.
但加上罚时后，他们仍然处在排位前三之中
Meaning they would go through to the semifinal
意味着他们将直接晋级半决赛
to battle it out with ACCIONA Sainz and the fastest qualifiers, X-44
与ACCIONA Sainz队和最快的X-44队一决高下
for a spot in the final.
争夺决赛位置
Today, it was a great day,
精彩的一天
because at the end of the day we went in qualifying.
因为在最后我们晋级了
It's uh a great result,
结果不错
uh, it was a tough battle,
名次的争抢上比较艰难
a few mistakes from other driver with quite big crashes,
其他车手有一些失误和事故
so it was a tough day with an intense fight with Rosberg's team.
这一天不容易，与RXR队之间的竞争很激烈
Finally we, we want the qualification
我们希望拿下这场排位
because we don't make mistakes,
因为我们的失误更少
and that's the different point.
这就是区别
With the qualifying action over,
随着排位赛的落幕
it was time for the relentless Saudi sun to set on the first day of Extreme E action.
沙特上空毒辣的太阳也终于要下山了
The beauty of the desert doesn't stop at night.
沙漠的美景并不止步于晚上
As after the sun dips below the horizon,
落日沉没到地平线之下后
the night sky illuminates in a way you will never see in populated cities.
夜空以一种大城市中未有的方式照亮大地
To the ancient people of the region, the stars played an important everyday part in life.
这些星星对于古时生活在此的人们有很重要的作用
Acting both as a road map to navigate the vast terrains.
一方面作为这片巨大沙漠的地图
and helping predict the many seasons that occur in the Saudi Arabian Desert.
另一方面帮助预测沙特阿拉伯沙漠的季节
The location of the moon or the sun,
月亮或太阳的位置
is very significant for us to know the lunar calendar or the solar calendar.
对于我们了解阳历或阴历是很重要的
This way, we know the different seasons.
通过这样的方式，我们可以区分不同的季节
For them to use the stars was very, very crucial
对于这些人，利用星星是很重要的技能
because of the nature of European peninsula.
因为欧洲半岛的天然特性
It's a harsh desert
这是个残酷的沙漠
where it has both extremes, very extreme cold in the winter,
这里有极低温的严寒
and then extreme heat in the in the summer.
也有极高温的酷暑
Of course, they relied on the stars to travel at night more than the daytime,
当然，他们更多是借助星星在夜晚出行而不是白天
to escape the heat of the sun.
为了避开日光的炎热
And also because of the long distances that they had cross for them.
因为他们要长途跋涉
That was very important to know where the water sources are
所以了解水源的位置，
where the next villages are,
了解村庄的位置，
the next oasis might be
下一个绿洲可能的位置，是很重要的
For them to just keep alive basically.
对于他们来说基本就是为了生存
For them to know the stars,
观星定位对于他们
know their location was so common sense that even kids know the stars.
是很基本的常识，甚至孩子们都知道如何观星
If you were to ask an Arab person,
如果你问一位阿拉伯人
do you know about the sky ,
你了解这片天空吗
he would be shame on you,
他会为你感到丢脸
how can I not know the ceiling of my own house?
我怎么能不了解我自家的屋顶？
While some gazed up at the starry skies above the Saudi deserts,
有些人在仰望沙漠上的星空的时候
many of the Extreme E teams were still hard at work.
Extreme E的队员们仍然在努力工作
Preparing for what day two of the Desert X-Prix would bring.
为X-Prix的第二天做好准备
Next time on Electric Odyssey,
下期Electric Odyssey中
we finally get to see what happened
我们终于能看到
when the teams lined up to go wheel to wheel racing.
各车队轮对轮竞争
Side by side now,
三车并排前进
Carlos Sainz is in the lead here.
Carlos Sainz抽头
Loeb追上他了！
Loeb's got him!
字幕：Lee-7723